Hi, I'm Lluís Estapé
and for the Qwen Cloud
Hackathon I built BoardRoom, which is a
tool that reviews printed circuit board
designs using a team of AI agents that
actually argue with each other. So let me
show you the problem it solves first.
If you send a board to fabrication with a
missing decoupling capacitor or a
silkscreen label printed over a pad, you'll
find out three weeks later and a few hundred
euros later. So I pointed BoardRoom at a
real KiCad board, the StickHub USB demo,
and this is what it came up with. Six
findings, which are power rails with mixed
copper widths, silkscreen overlapping
pads on the USB footprints, and missing fiducials.
Every single finding has to cite a
real tool call. This ID comes from an
actual query against the board file. So if
an agent makes a claim it can't back
with evidence, the finding is rejected
automatically before it reaches you.
Across every benchmark run, both
configurations, the hallucination rate
was exactly zero.
So how does it work? The board goes
in here, five specialists inspect it:
power integrity, signal integrity,
connectivity, DFM and layout, and firmware
bring-up. Each one talks to KiCad through
the Model Context Protocol, and each one
can only touch the tools in its own
lane, and that's enforced in code.
They file findings, a Moderator
collects them and signs off the review.
All of it runs on Qwen models on Alibaba
Cloud Model Studio.
To have a better understanding of the
output, the results are shown in an
orbit map where every finding is linked
to the nets and components it touches.
Because the layout critic is a multimodal
model, it looks at the rendered board
and draws a box around each defect, right
on the copper.
I have now dropped an example of a
debate to show you the feature between
the AI agents. When two specialists
disagree, a Moderator runs a bounded
debate: two rounds, one extra measurement
each, then rules based on the evidence,
not on who argued harder. So it's
full disclosure, this transcript is
synthetic, the engine works and is
tested. But across my whole benchmark,
the specialists never actually disagreed.
So I'd rather show you the mechanism than
a fake argument.
One last important question is to ask if
a team of agents is actually better than
one big one. I measured it with six boards,
twelve planted defects, two runs each. On
finding the defects, it's a tie. The team led
by one defect out of twelve, which is noise, so
I'm not going to claim otherwise. But
looking at the cost, the team burns two
and a half times more tokens and costs nearly
three times less, because five small
models doing more work are far cheaper
than one big model doing less. So routing
by role beats routing by model size.
Thank you for watching and I hope you
find my project useful. Special thanks to
Qwen AI for creating this hackathon.